David Monahan

San Antonio, Texas, United States

david.monahan57@gmail.com

210 636 6254

linkedin.com/in/david-monahan-b8bb84221

Summary

Information Technology Manager with over 20-years of leading all areas of product life cycle. Developing a new product is both an exciting and challenging task. From initial ideas to research, development, testing, and prototyping, to full implementation is where dreams become reality.

Experience



🛂 Researcher Phd Candidate

University at Buffalo

Jan 2016 - Present (6 years 11 months +)

Specialized courses in Parallel Algorithms, Discrete Structures, Java, MATLAB, Applied Probability, Psychological Statistics, and Scientific Inquiry in Psychology to complete research and analysis.

Information Technology Operations Manager

Lockheed Martin

Jun 2012 - Sep 2013 (1 year 4 months)

Managed a team of 5 Linux Network Engineers (Red Hat Enterprise Linux and Centos) and 6 Radio Electronics Technicians for the Battlespace Command and Control Center.

Obtained 100-percent network uptime and area coverage of the Arbian Gulf Area of Responsibility

Received Management Incentive Compensation Award for exceeding projected timelines and bringing in over \$1 million in new business

Received Project Completion bonus. Completed project 6-months ahead of schedule



Project Manager

Lockheed Martin

Jul 2011 - Jun 2012 (1 year)

By name request, Space and Naval Warfare Systems Command, joined program Process Improvement team for Battlespace Command and Control Center upgrade

Tripled the Infrastructure, secure/nonsecure equipment requirements, and number of operator positions for Air Comtrol Squadron weapons/surveillance officers to support three areas of responsibility Received project completion bonus



Information Technology Operations Manager

Lockheed Martin

Apr 2010 - Aug 2011 (1 year 5 months)

Managed a team of 3 Linux Network Engineers and 4 Radio Electronics Technicians for the Battlespace Command and Control System.

Obtained 100-percent network uptime and area coverage of Iraq

Received Project Completion bonus. System redeployed ~ completed project three months ahead of schedule



Information Technology Operations Manager

Lockheed Martin

Sep 2008 - Apr 2010 (1 year 8 months)

Managed a team of 6 Linux Network Engineers and 6 Radio Electronics Technicians for the Battlespace Command and Control System.

Increased the number of positions for Air Comtrol Squadron weapons/surveillance officers by 10x to support two areas of responsibility

Obtained 100-percent network uptime and area coverage of the country of Afghanistan Received Project Completion bonus. Completed project four months ahead of schedule



Adjunct Professor

University of Arkansas Grantham Mar 2004 - Sep 2008 (4 years 7 months)

College of SCIENCE, ENGINEERING, AND TECHNOLOGY

*CS263 Programming in C

CS285 Programming in C++

*CT262 Microprocessor Systems Engineering (Assembler)

*Accreditation from the Engineering Technology Accreditation Commission of ABET for the Bachelor of Science in Electronics Engineering Technology program.



🔼 Adjunct Professor

Northwest Vista College

Jan 2002 - Aug 2008 (6 years 8 months)

Department of Computer Science, Technology and Business

BMGT 1309 Information Project Management

COSC 1315 Introduction to Computer Programming

ITSY 1300 Fundamentals of Information Security

ITSE 1307 Introduction to C++ Programming

ITNW 1308 Implementing and Supporting Client Operating Systems



Superintendent, Airfield Systems Maintenance

United States Air Force

Nov 1998 - Mar 2004 (5 years 5 months)

Windows OS Air Traffic Control Tower console. Manages and directs communications systems maintenance facilities and resources. Included are functions of installing, maintaining, repairing, overhauling, deploying, and modifying. Plans and organizes maintenance activities. Prepares and analyzes reports encompassing siting, deploying, maintaining, installing, repairing, and removing communications systems, and related equipment.



✓ Site Operations Manager

United States Air Force

Oct 1996 - Oct 1998 (2 years 1 month)

Manages the design, installation, interconnection, operation and defense of networks in support of data systems to provide secure, non-secure, and coalition information exchange requirements at a remote site. Additional responsibilities include, to supervise the operation and performance of preventive maintenance on both hardware and software systems; including radio, telephone, cryptographic, network and data systems, to enhance the overall functions of communication and command and control.



Quality Assurance Quality Control Manager

United States Air Force

Oct 1994 - Oct 1996 (2 years 1 month)

Supervises, directs, and controls collection, auditing, evaluation, and analysis of data to include auditing source data for accuracy, timeliness, and compliance with directives. Supervises analysis of deficiencies in areas such as equipment performance, materiel consumption, scheduling, management, and resources; their impact on the maintenance mission; and results of corrective actions. Reviews and approves written reports and special studies for presentation to senior leaders. Coordinates with appropriate information management/processing centers to ensure automated systems capability and compatibility with customer requirements are met. Forwards requirements and enhancements to higher headquarters for approval.



Workcenter Supervisor, Air Traffic Control Maintenance

United States Air Force

Oct 1988 - Oct 1994 (6 years 1 month)

Supervises ground radio maintenance activities for UHF/VHF single/multichannel radios, Air Traffic Control Consoles, recorders, etc. Oversees work in progress and reviews completed repairs for sound maintenance practices. Establishes requirements for maintenance equipment, support equipment, tools, and spare parts. Interprets inspection findings and determines adequacy of corrective action. Reviews and ensures compliance with maintenance publications and procedures. Identifies maintenance problem areas and recommends corrective action.



Electronic Technician, Ground Radio

United States Air Force

Feb 1984 - Oct 1988 (4 years 9 months)

Air Traffic Control and Landing Systems (ATCALS) technician. Assembling, installing, repairing, troubleshooting, and maintaining electronic components and systems. Sourcing or fabricating replacement parts for electronic systems.

Education



Northcentral University

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Computer Science

2002 - Jul 2024

All required coursework completed. Dissertation in work.

Northcentral University

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Computer Science Nov 2001 - Oct 2002

Thomas Edison State University

Bachelor of Applied Science - BASc, Computer Science

Nov 1997 - May 2001

Accreditation from the Engineering Technology Accreditation Commission of ABET for the Bachelor of Science in Electronics Engineering Technology program.

Community College of the Air Force

Associate of Science - AS, Electrical and Electronics Engineering Jan 1990 - Mar 1992

Licenses & Certifications

PH125.1x: Data Science: R Basics - HarvardX - An Online Learning Initiative by Harvard University through edX

PH125.3x: Data Science: Probility - HarvardX - An Online Learning Initiative by Harvard University through edX

Linux Essentials - Network Development Group

Skills

Equipment Maintenance • Engineering • Network Infrastructure • Performance Analysis • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Cloud Computing • Network Security • Linux • Cryptography • Software Installation

Honors & Awards



National Honor Society - Tau Sigma National Honor Society

Tau Sigma is an academic honor society designed specifically to "recognize and promote the academic excellence and involvement of transfer students.

http://www.tausigmanhs.org/

Management Incentive Compensation Award - Lockheed Martin Jun 2013

This Plan is established to provide a further incentive to selected employees to promote the success of Lockheed Martin Corporation by providing an opportunity to receive additional compensation for above average performance measured against individual and business unit goals.

Master Bit Manipulator (Assembler Language) - Control Data Corporation Sep 1986